Marcos Ribeiro da Silva

Web Developer Jr.

marcao.demolay@gmail.com github/marcostupan +55 11 96463-2207

About Me

Based in Ceará, Brazil. Professional transitioning to a programming career with 8 months of experience. Completed the Programmer Profession (Fullstack) course in December 2023 and the Dev Samurai Front-End course Feb. 2024 to the present. Completed more than 18 projects, using technologies such as HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, React, React Native, Sass, Bootstrap, Tailwind, Next.js, PostgreSQL, MariaDB, and Express.

Professional Experience

Web Developer

Freelancer August/2023 - Present

- Started studying programming during college, developing personal websites. In August 2023, I started specializing, working on my first projects as a Freelancer, completing more than 18 projects since then. Some professional and others for study and to improve my skills.
- Projects using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Bootstrap, Next.js, among others.

Accountant

Self-employed 2019 - Present

Providing consulting and auditing services, as well as accounting for companies.

Internal Auditor Latam

BNP Paribas

2017 - 2019

- Responsible for internal audits in Latin America.
- Participation in global audits and meetings with international teams.
- Conducted audits in Latin American countries such as Peru, Colombia, and Chile.
- Conducted meetings in English, Spanish, and Portuguese.

External Auditor

Deloitte 2014 to 2017

- Worked on global audits, including collaboration with teams in the USA. (main Clients: DowChemical, CSN, ViaVarejo, etc).
- Participated in the Deloitte Audit Inovation team to implement technologies in auditing. Ex: Tableau for audit analysis. SAP ECC.
- Facilitator of training on tools, frameworks, and accounting and auditing rules.

Education

>Programmer Profession

August 2023

Course taught by Professional Paulo Borges with a duration of 110 hours, covering front-end, backend, architecture and design patterns, cloud, among other knowledge in the world of systems development.

>Dev Samurai Front End

December 2023

Course taught by Professional Felipe Fontoura with a duration of 60 hours, covering front-end, databases, programming logic, React, Sass, and Bootstrap.

>Bachelor's Degree in Accounting

Trevisan School of Business

2017

4-year undergraduate course in Accounting Sciences.

Languages

English: Advanced

Spanish: Advanced

Portuguese: Native

Featured Projects

The Fit Club

Project with a lot of animation using React. It was interesting because I was able to learn how to create animations and color scales.

See the site. https://fit-club-website-lyart.vercel.app/>

Cara Store

Ecommerce project using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. It was interesting because I was able to learn more about the Mobile First concept and create a beautiful ecommerce store.

See the site. https://cara-store-six.vercel.app/>

Star Wars Characters

The first project I did using JavaScript consuming an API. It was interesting to observe the power of the language and use libraries.

See the site. https://star-wars-characters-iota.vercel.app/>